<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://wiki.teewallz.dev/blog</id>
    <title>Teewallz'z Knowledge Hole Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://wiki.teewallz.dev/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Teewallz'z Knowledge Hole Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://wiki.teewallz.dev/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My first diary]]></title>
        <id>https://wiki.teewallz.dev/blog/my-first-blog-post</id>
        <link href="https://wiki.teewallz.dev/blog/my-first-blog-post"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After struggling with undiagnosed ADHD for 30 years and being a disorganised mess, I am taking inspiration from Digital Gardens and am using this site to organise my knowledge and thoughts.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After struggling with undiagnosed ADHD for 30 years and being a disorganised mess, I am taking inspiration from Digital Gardens and am using this site to organise my knowledge and thoughts.</p><p>I have also never written a blog or wiki before as I always thought 'who cares' and 'why bother?'</p><p>But after finding Joel Hooks' <a href="https://joelhooks.com/digital-garden/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Garden blog</a>, specifically the following line from Amy Hoy's <a href="https://stackingthebricks.com/how-blogs-broke-the-web/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">how-blogs-broke-the-web</a></p><blockquote><p>We've moved away from hand crafted home pages that required us to curate and present our best content in the best light.</p></blockquote><p>Upon reading these sites, I have reconnected with something I have longed for and forgotten -- a basic ass site that you throw your thoughts at with little regard as to whom sees.
A site that you cultivate and grow for your own mental health that another digital traveller may come across for a minute or so, glance at it for a moment and continue on.</p><p>While this 'Blog' section partially breaks this idea, I believe that a diary of sorts may be good for myself in organising thoughts that are infact time-relevent (i.e. life events, feelings etc) that can't be organised in a tagged/hierarchical structure.</p><p>I began by creating a Notion database for my thoughts and knowledge (Specifically Thomas Frank's <a href="https://www.notion.so/templates/ultimate-brain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ultimate Brain</a>)
While this was a great starting point, Notion lacks any kind of 'performative' nature to it. A 'reaching out into the void'..ness.
Covid has made me realised just how connected we all are, and that locking ourselves away and not reaching out into the vastness of humanity is a death sentence.
Scrolling through endless Facebook/Reddit/Tik Tok algorithms away from the vast gardens of human creation.</p><p>TODO:</p><ul><li>Performance -&gt; Accountability</li><li>ADHD - Memory issues</li></ul><p>After my ADHD diagnosis, the resulting medication and moving from Australia to Poland, I have finally felt that I can create for creations sake.
I have endured through childhood abuse, ADHD, hating myself, depression and this will be a tool to prove to myself that I have worth.</p><p>This is my Garden.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Waller</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/teewallz</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>